THOMAS ALEXANDER

http://www.whitewhim.ca/ thomasalexander2718@gmail.com github.com/whitewhim2718 (902) 800-2143

PERSONAL STATEMENT

As a graduate of Mount Allison University's physics, mathematics and computer science programs I have been given plenty of oppurtunities to demonstrate a very strong work ethic. I am also a very quick learner and quickly pick up new techniques and skills. I have had plenty of work experience in a variety of jobs, from labour to scientific research. I am interested in entry-level summer employment.

EDUCATION

Undergraduate School on Experimental Quantum Information Processing

May 2013 - June 2013

Institute for Quantum Computing, Waterloo, ON

Bachelor of Science, First Class Honours with distinction: Physics, double minor: Computer Science and Mathematics GPA 3.7

September 2010 - May 2014

Mount Allison University, Sackville, NB

Career History

Undergraduate Research, Institute For Quantum Computing

Current

- Working with researchers to design an experiment to improve the contrast of neutron interferometry phase measurements, using Bayesian MCMC methods.
- Designed and developed a neutron interferometry control system to be installed at National Institute for Standards and Technology in Gaithersburg, MD.
- Implementation of likelihood functions on GPGPUs.

Software Development Intern, G2 Research

Summer 2012

- Development of cellular tracking and analysis software.
- Setup OpenStreetMaps rendering server.
- Product and software research.

IT Manager, The Argosy Newspaper

2011-2012

- Setup and maintenance of Drupal news site.
- Cloud server setup on NGINX/PHP-FPM stack.
- Serviced companies equipment and network.

MSDS Database Creation, Maritime Beauty

Summer 2011

- Setup a Material Safety Data Sheet database for Maritime Beauty on proprietary software.
- Networked with outside companies to develop relationships and acquire information.

Plastic Recycler, Whitestar Plastics

Summer 2010

- Baling of recycled plastic.
- Plastic Sorting.
- Collection of plastics.

Production Manager, Skratch That

2009-2010

• Production manager of an entrepreneurial startup that was part of the Junior Achievement program. Responsible for production of the companys product and production implementation. Skratch That won Company of the Year in all of Atlantic Canada for 2010.

Produce Clerk, Pete's Frootique

Summer 2009

- Stocking of produce displays.
- Cycling of displays.
- Aiding customers.

Returns Sorter, ASCO Warehouse

Summer 2008

- Sorting of returns.
- Mailing of phonebooks.

Hockey Referee, Bedford Minor Hockey

2006-2010

• Officiate hockey games.

• Timekeep hockey games.

SKILLS

Physics: Neutron Interferometry, Quantum Mechanics, Quantum Computing, Electrodynamics, Optics, Solid State Physics, Classical Mechanics, Analog Electronics, Digital Electronics

Hardware: Arduino, GPGPU programming, Cloud computing, Analog Electronics

Programming: Java, Scala/Akka, HTML5/CSS, JavaScript/Node.js, Mathematica, LATEX, Python/scipy, SQL, C, Cuda C, OpenCl, git, svn, MongoDB

Programming Concepts: Algorithms Analysis, Object Orientated Programming , Unit Testing, Quantum Computing, Computer Architecture, Functional Programming, Data Structures, Databases, Networking, Neural Networking, Basic AI

Operating Systems: Linux, Windows, Mac OSX

LEADERSHIP ACTIVITIES

Tutor, Physics and Computer Science	2010 - Current
Awards and Honors	
4'th Place, The 2012 Northeast North America Regional ACM Contest Preliminary	2012
3'rd Place , Robot's East Atlantic Championships	2010
1'st Place, Robot's East Atlantic Championships	2009
1'st Place, Robot's East Atlantic Championships	2008